hi there I'm Luis and I'd like to chat
嗨， 我是路易斯，我想聊聊
it up about chatbots
关于聊天机器人
after that awful intro you know it can
在那个糟糕的介绍之后，你知道它可以
only go uphill from here so I'd like to
只是从这里上山所以我想
talk to you about the history of
和你谈谈历史
chatbots we're gonna crack open some
聊天机器人我们要打开一些
chatbots and show you the machine
聊天机器人，并告诉你机器
learning the models that are used to
得知是用来模型
make chatbots work today and at the end
使聊天机器人在今天和最后工作
of this presentation you can do
您可以做这个演示文稿
something super exciting you're gonna do
你将要做的超级刺激的事情
some live coding and this kind of
一些现场编码和这种
scariest thing these things could go
这件事情最可怕的事情
wrong but we're gonna do some live
错了， 但我们要做点活
coding and I'm gonna show you a very
编码， 我会告诉你一个非常
basic chat bot super exciting
基本聊天机器人超级精彩
presentation today let's get started
今天的演讲让我们开始吧
first of all what is the chat bot well
首先，什么是聊天机器人以及
it's a bot that chats pretty
这是一个聊天很棒的机器人
self-explanatory what's not so
不言自明的是什么不是这样
self-explanatory is all of the benefits
不言自明是所有的好处
that chat BOTS can bring to us ok so
该聊天机器人可以为我们带来 这么好的
they use AI in neural networks super
他们在超级神经网络中使用AI
advanced technology so that's really
先进的技术真的如此
cool progressing technology and the
很酷的进步技术和
biggest advantage of chat BOTS is that
聊天BOTS的最大优点是
they take voice and text instructions so
他们接受语音和文字说明
text instructions so that's huge because
文本说明因此非常大
using our voice using language that's
使用我们的语言使用语言
how humans have interacted with the
人类如何与人交往
world for thousands of years so before
几千年前的世界
we had our iPhones all we had was our
我们拥有的所有 iPhone 都是我们的
language so that's huge we've evolved to
语言因此我们已经发展到了巨大的程度
use this our language is super complex
使用这个我们的语言非常复杂
and we're used to using it all the time
我们习惯一直使用它
so why not allow us to interact with our
那么为什么不让我们与我们互动呢？
technology that way instead of forcing
技术而不是强迫
us to physically be somewhere and touch
我们身体在某处和触摸
a screen or stroke a key so chop us are
一个屏幕或一个按键，所以砍我们
huge for that use our natural language
巨大的使用我们的自然语言
to interact with tech another advantage
与科技互动的另一个好处
always on 24/7 baby just leave it
总是在24/7宝贝就好了
plugged in you don't need to pay it you
插入你不需要支付你
don't need to feed it you don't need to
不需要养活它，你不必
water it you definitely shouldn't water
浇水它你绝对不应该浇水
it just leave it plugged in runs all day
它只是让它整天都在运行
no problems also never judges you now
没有问题也永远不会评判你
this is really
这是真的
big because in some cases you can think
很大，因为在某些情况下你可以思考
of like you can imagine like a therapist
就像你可以想象的像治疗师一样
situation you might be embarrassed and
情况下，你可能会尴尬，
it might take you a while to to open up
你可能需要一段时间才能打开
to that therapist about things about
关于事情的治疗师
yourself that you're sensitive about and
自己要对敏感和
you're shy about chatbots don't have
你很害羞聊天机器人没有
that problem we're gonna talk a little
那个问题我们会谈一点
bit about a therapist chatbot one of the
关于治疗师聊天机器人之一
very first chatbots actually and this
实际上这是第一个聊天机器人
was one of its main draws does it never
从来没有它的主要吸引力之一
judged you cuz it's a robot and robots
判断你是因为它是一个机器人和机器人
don't have feelings yet let's talk about
没有感情，但让我们谈谈
the founder of chatbot and one of the
chatbot的创始人之一
people who made it super popular
让它超级流行的人
technology so first we're gonna talk
技术首先我们要谈谈
about Joseph Weizenbaum and he created
关于Joseph Weizenbaum和他创造的
the first ever chat bot now this chat
现在这个聊天的第一个聊天机器人
bot was named Eliza and Joseph
机器人被命名为伊丽莎和约瑟夫
Weizenbaum was an MIT professor when he
Weizenbaum 当他是麻省理工学院的教授
created this and he wrote the chat put
创造了这个，他写了聊天放
in his own programming language which is
在他自己的编程语言中
super impressive also super impressive
超级令人印象深刻也令人印
Eliza his chat bot was so realistic that
Eliza 他的聊天机器人非常逼真
his assistant was interacting with it
他的助手正在与它互动
one day and she actually asked him to
有一天，她实际上问他
step out of the room so that she could
走出房间，这样她就可以
have a private conversation with Eliza
与Eliza进行私人谈话
so that's insane okay
这太疯狂了
assistants are telling their bosses to
助理告诉他们的老板
leave the room so they can talk to a
离开房间， 这样他们就可以和他们说话了
computer in 1960 man this bot was
计算机在1960年这个 机器 人是谁
created in 1960 so a little bit more
在1960年更是 这样一点点建立
modern about thirty years into the
现代约三十年进入
future
未来
we've got Zhang Xiao Leung I probably
我可能是张小梁
butchered his name I hope it's close to
我希望它接近他的名字
correct but he created this company
没错，但他创建了这家公司
called WeChat very popular messaging app
叫微信非常受欢迎的消息应用程序
and on the back end more engineering
并在后端更多的工程
side of things it's a very easy platform
事情的一面是一个非常容易的平台
to create chat BOTS for so lots of
为这么多人创建聊天BOTS
businesses have chat bots on WeChat so
企业对微信聊天机器人 等等
that you can text the business and ask
你可以发短信给业务并提出要求
it questions and the chat bot will
它的问题和聊天机器人会
respond intelligently
聪明地回应
you instead of having to have like a
你不必拥有像
call center or something a business can
呼叫中心或企业可以做的事情
set up a chat bot on WeChat to answer
在微信上设置一个聊天机器人来回答
tons of common questions that customers
客户众多的常见问题
might have so that's a little about a
可能有一点关于a
little bit about the history of chat
关于聊天历史的一点点
BOTS and you know starting from the very
BOTS，你知道从最开始
beginning and jumping forward a bit to
开始并向前跳了一下
someone who helped blow this technology
帮助吹制这项技术的人
up and popularize it to where it is
把它推广到它所在的地方
today so now I'd like to compare the
今天所以现在我想比较一下
traditional user experience of having an
具有传统的用户体验
app on your phone say and you know
手机上的应用程序说你知道
tapping around two different screens
敲击两个不同的屏幕
versus a newer type of user experience
与较新型的用户体验相比
where we've got chat BOTS so with a
我们在哪里聊天BOTS所以
traditional app you know it's on your
传统的应用程序，你知道它在你的
phone your tap in your scroll in your
在你的滚动条中点按你的水龙头
typing you know we're all used to that
输入你知道我们已经习惯了
type of user interaction and it works
用户交互的类型， 它的工作原理
great okay it works great for tons of
非常好，它适用于大量的
applications for tons of things that we
我们应用了大量的东西
want to do but chat BOTS allow us this
我想做但聊天BOTS允许我们这个
new functionality of interacting with
与...交互的新功能
things with our voice okay so I don't
我们声音的东西还可以，所以我没有
have to be holding a piece of technology
必须持有一项技术
in my hand I can shout at something
在我手里， 我可以大喊大叫
across the room and it will talk back to
在房间里，它会顶嘴
me and ask me like oh did you mean this
我问问我哦你的意思是这个吗？
did you mean this and it can ask me for
你的意思是这个，它可以问我
specifics and that's just really hard to
细节，这只是真的很难
do with traditional hard coded touching
做传统的硬编码触摸
tapping scrolling apps that were used to
点击以前使用的滚动应用
on our phone
在我们的手机上
so chat BOTS really open up a ton of
所以聊天机器人真正打开一吨
possibilities they're used everywhere ok
他们在各处都可以使用的可能性
used in banking used in workflow
用于工作流程中的银行业务
applications used in content used to
用于以往内容的应用程序
create content sometimes I actually
我有时创造内容
remember an example of a guy who made a
记住一个做出一个人的例子
chatbot to make recipes for him and he
聊天机器人为他和他做食谱
baked one of the cakes that the chat bot
烘焙其中一个聊天机器人的蛋糕
gave him a recipe for it came out awful
给了他一个食谱，它出来很可怕
like one of the main ingredients was
像其中一个主要成分是
ketchup
番茄酱
but yeah so chatbots shouldn't be used
但是，所以不应该使用聊天机器人
everywhere in every case but they can be
在每种情况下无处不在，但他们可以
used a lot of places
用过很多地方
they're very useful in a lot of places
它们在很多地方非常有用
so let's talk about three different
所以我们来谈谈三个不同的
types of chatbots and kind of like
聊天机器人的类型和类似的
different levels of usability so at the
不同级别的可用性因此
highest level we've got contextual now
最高级别我们现在有了上下文
this is a chatbot that understands you
这是一个了解你的聊天机器人
okay it's like it gives this really good
好吧，它就像它给这真的很好
illusion of understanding what you're
理解你是什么的错觉
saying so here's an example of a Pizza
这么说这是比萨饼的一个例子
ordering chat bot so you say hey I'd
订购聊天机器人让你说嘿我
like to order a pizza and the Chapa
喜欢点披萨和Chapa
remembers that the last time you ordered
记得你最后一次订购
and it might even be time related maybe
它甚至可能与时间有关
this guy ordered a pizza at like 8:30
这家伙在8点30分订了披萨
a.m. last time and the chat BOTS like
我最后一次和聊天BOTS一样
hey last time you ordered at 8:30 a.m.
嘿， 你最后一次订购上午8:30
you ordered this thing's chat BOTS use
你订购了这个东西的聊天BOTS使用
information like the time previous order
以前订单的时间等信息
history things like that to get more of
这样的历史事情可以获得更多
an idea to get context and to infer
获得背景和推断的想法
things about what you want out of them
关于你想要什么的事情
so that's the highest level of Chapa
这 是Chapa的最高水平
interaction we've also got a step lower
互动我们也低了一步
these are much easier to program and
这些更容易编程和
this is what the majority of chat bots
这是大多数聊天机器人
are out in production out in the wild
在野外生产出来
today our keyword recognition based chat
今天我们的关键字识别聊天
BOTS so these do what they say the name
BOTS 所以这些就是他们所说的名字
self-explanatory you talk to the chat
不言自明， 你说聊天
bot and all it does is look for certain
机器人，它所做的一切都是肯定的
keywords in your speech to either
你的演讲中的关键词
present you with more options or
为您提供更多选择或
directly give you a solution to some
直接给你一些解决方案
question you have so here we see Casey
你有问题，我们在这里看到凯西
Phillips asking something to point bot
菲利普斯问东西指向机器人
and point bot notices the words Auto
并指向机器人注意到单词Auto
logout transaction and gives him a
注销交易并给他一个
perfect answer telling him exactly how
完美的答案告诉他究竟是怎
to do the thing that he's asking
做他要问的事情
and on the lowest level oh my gosh these
并在最低水平哦，我的天哪，这些
are so annoying these are so annoying
很烦人，这些都很烦人
okay I called Costco the other day and I
好吧，前几天我打电话给好市多和我
want to get in touch with the photo
想要与照片取得联系
Department pick up the phone
部门拿起电话
hey Costco can I talk to the photo
嘿，Costco，我可以和照片对话
department nope greeted with a bot that
部门都能跟得上迎接僵尸那
says please press 1 for groceries please
请按1买杂货
press 2 for upper management please
按2， 高层管理人员，请
press 3 for the vacuum section and it's
按3 表示真空部分
so annoying because it gives you this
太烦人了，因为它给你这个
menu you can't select something from it
菜单你不能从中选择一些东西
right away and it can't understand
马上就无法理解
anything that you're saying so these are
你所说的任何事情都是如此
super annoying sometimes with point but
有时带点但非常烦人
here it's much nicer because you're
在这里它更好，因为你
presented with a list of options and you
提供了一个选项列表和你
can easily see which one applies to you
很容易看出哪一个适用于你
but for much less sophisticated chat
但对于不太复杂的聊天
BOTS like little Costco bot that I was
BOTS就像我一样的小Costco机器人
humping fun with yesterday it can be
驼峰乐趣昨天它可以
super annoying so this is the lowest
超级烦人所以这是最低的
level of chat bot the chat bot
聊天机器人聊天机器人的水平
technology today so how does it chat bot
技术今天如何聊天机器人
work oh man you're in for a treat we're
工作哦，男人， 你是一个享受我们的待遇
gonna talk about a lot of things that
要谈谈很多事情
you or I really don't understand so you
你或我真的不明白你
got your phone made in a factory
让你的手机在工厂生产
somewhere and you've got some messaging
在某个地方，你有一些消息
apps on it maybe you've got WeChat maybe
应用就可能你也许有微信
you've got Facebook messenger maybe
你可能有Facebook的信使
you've got slack these are all super
你已经松弛了这些都是超级的
popular messaging apps with lots of chat
流行的消息应用程序，有很多聊天
bots on them and you open up your app
他们的机器人，你打开你的应用程序
and you say something to a chat bot the
你对聊天机器人说了些什么
chat bot breaks down your language using
聊天机器人使用它来分解你的语言
something called natural language
称为自然语言的东西
processing and what natural language
处理和自然语言
processing does or NLP is it tries to
处理确实或NLP被它试图
interpret your words in the way that
用这种方式解释你的话
another human would that's the basic
另一个人就是基本的
idea of NLP
NLP的想法
that analysis on your language
分析你的语言
it's then stored in laking knowledgebase
然后将其存储在知识库中
and that can be used for training data
这可以用于培训数据
to retrain the chat BOTS so it gets
重新训练聊天BOTS所以它得到了
smarter over time and it can also go
随着时间的推移更聪明，它也可以去
into a data store like we saw with the
成数据存储就像我们看到与
pizza bot earlier where you can really
披萨机器人早些时候你真的可以
person
人
as a chatbot to each individual so it
作为每个人的聊天机器人所以它
can remember each interaction you had
能记住你的每次互动
with it it can do cool things like order
有了它，它可以做很酷的事情，如订单
you the same pizza that you had last
你，你还有最后 一样比萨饼
time so that's the high-level idea of
时间，这是高层次的想法
how a chatbot works so natural language
聊天机器人如何运作如此自然的语言
processing to break that down a little
加工打破这一点
bit more it can do things like
它可以做更多的事情
translation information retrieval
翻译信息检索
sentiment analysis so like applying and
情绪分析就像申请和
emotion to the things that you said like
对 你所说的事情的情感
is what you said angry is what you said
是你所说的生气是你所说的
happy things like that question
喜欢这个问题的快乐事情
answering so yeah those are some
回答所以是的，那些是一些
applications of natural language
自然语言的应用
processing how do we do natural language
处理我们如何做自然语言
processing well we've got something
处理得好我们有东西
called generative and selective models
称为生成和选择模型
so generative is like a it generates
所以生成就像它产生的一样
okay it's a machine learning model that
好吧，这是一个机器学习模型
generates new text we've also got
生成我们也有的新文本
selective models which perform actions
执行动作的选择模型
that maximize good and minimize bad here
在这里最大限度地发挥好的作用
is an example of another of another
是另一个的另一个例子
machine learning model used this is an
机器学习模型使用这是一个
example of two different neural networks
两个不同神经网络的例子
one has a ton of different training data
一个人有大量不同的训练数据
and it's going into these neurons this
和它的进入这些神经元这
it does neural network math magic okay
它做神经网络数学魔术没关系
we don't need to worry about the math
我们不需要担心数学问题
and what neural networks are right now
什么神经网络现在
but basically it gets fed a lot of
但基本上它得到了很多
training data it produces some result
训练数据会产生一些结果
and then it's trained again with a
然后再用a训练
smaller set of training data with more
较小的训练数据集
variants and what this does is it can
变体以及它的作用是什么
prevent things from getting it can
防止事情得到它可以
prevent the network from getting too
防止网络过度
biased or learning things that we don't
有偏见或学习我们不做的事情
want it to like Microsoft experience
希望它喜欢微软的经验
with its teh tweets robot a few years
用它的推文机器人几年
back we've also got reinforcement
我们也得到了加强
learning
学习
so what reinforcement learning is is
所以强化学习是什么
this thing where you've got an agent or
这件事，你有一个代理人或
like a you can think of it as like a
就像你可以把它想象成一个
character in a game and he's influencing
游戏中的角色，他正在影响
his environment and the basic idea
他的环境和基本理念
behind reinforcement learning is it
强化学习的背后是它
wants to maximize the positives and
想要最大化积极因素
minimize the negatives if you want to
如果你愿意，尽可能减少负面影响
see a really cool example of this look
看到这个外观真的很酷的例子
up Marv oh and somebody uses
Marv哦，有人用
reinforcement learning to make AI play a
加强学习使AI发挥作用
game of Mario which is super cool so
马里奥的比赛， 这是非常酷的
another type of model used in NLP is
NLP中使用的另一种模型是
sequence to sequence now what this is is
顺序排序现在这是什么
it uses two steps an encoder step and a
它使用两个步骤编码器步骤和a
decoder step so what the encoder step
解码器步骤那么编码器步骤
does is it takes sequences of characters
它是否需要一系列字符
or words and just bits of language and
或单词和语言和
it turns them into numbers
它把它们变成了数字
okay gives them a number representation
好吧给他们一个数字代表
and then it goes through a thought
然后它经历了一个想法
vector which is it's like a an
矢量，它就像一个
artificial kind of thinking process
人工的思维过程
where the decoder tries to think of a
解码器试图想到的地方
good response to the text that was
到了文本反响良好
encoded so what the decoder does is it
编码所以解码器的作用就是它
thinks of some numbers it generates some
想到它会产生一些数字
new numbers and decodes them back into
新号码并解码它们放回
words which is what we originally fed
我们最初喂的话
into the model so encoder turns the
进入模型，所以编码器转动
words into a number representation
单词表示数字
decoder thinks of some new numbers that
解码器想到了一些新的数字
it can use and turns those numbers into
它可以使用并将这些数字转换成
a word representation giving you your
一个单词表示给你你的
response here's an example of a sequence
这里的响应是一个序列的例子
to sequence mechanism they can use with
他们可以使用的序列机制
they can be used with multiple inputs
它们可以与多个输入一起使用
going into very few outputs to do cool
进入很少的输出做酷
things like translate Chinese into
像翻译中文的东西
English so it's a nice little image
英语所以这是一个很好的小形象
right there another type of model that
就在那里另一种模型
are used in chat BOTS are long
用于聊天BOTS很长
short-term memory units now the name is
短期记忆单位现在的名字是
kind of confusing and these confused me
有点混乱，这些让我困惑
for a long time but on a very basic
很长一段时间，但非常基本
level the idea behind these is each
这些背后的想法是各自的
building block of these networks they
他们构建这些网络
each have a
每个都有一个
short-term memory associated with them
与他们相关的短期记忆
and each layer can pass its short-term
每层都可以通过它的短期
memory on to the later levels of the
内存上的后来的水平
network so this is why it's called the
网络， 这就是为什么它被称为
long short-term memory they can only
他们只有长期的短暂记忆
retain small bits of memory but these
保留一小部分内存，但这些
small bits of memory are passed on layer
在图层上传递少量内存
by layer by layer to give the illusion
逐层给出幻觉
of long-term memory yeah here's some
长期记忆，是的，这里有一些
books on chatbots
关于聊天机器人的书籍
if you were curious to learn more about
如果你好奇， 更多地了解
them detailed explanation of what is a
他们详细解释了什么是
chatbot I'll let you ask your teacher
chatbot我会让你问你的老师
for this video on your own time because
这个视频在你自己的时间因为
we got to get through this presentation
我们得完成了这个演讲
to get to the live coding example here's
去现场编码例如，以下是
a nice little video on how chat BOTS
关于如何聊天BOTS的精彩小视频
work and finally the moment that you
工作，最后是你的那一刻
have all been waiting for
一直在等待
hopefully you're not bored out of your
希望你不会厌倦你的
minds and if you are we're gonna wake
心灵如果你是我们会被唤醒
you up okay we're gonna give you a
你好， 我们会给你一个
little wakey-wakey here cuz I'm gonna
我醒来的时候有点醒来， 因为我要去
code a chat bot live alright so if you
代码聊天机器人生活好，如果你
have no programming experience that's
没有编程经验
totally fine but I want to show you guys
完全没问题， 但我想告诉你们
some of the code because it's really
一些代码 ，因为它真的
cool
凉
and I think you'll be astounded at how
而且我觉得你会对如何感到震惊
easy this is so step 0 import US
这是第0步导入美国
programmers like to start counting from
程序员喜欢从开始计数
0 you'll you'll learn that if you don't
0如果你不这样做，你会知道的
have any if you haven't coded a lot yet
如果你还没有很多编码，那就有了
import oops
进口哎呀
from chatter bot import chat bot so
来自chatter bot导入聊天机器人所以
right here what we're doing is we're
就在这里，我们正在做的就是我们
taking this chatter bot package
采取这个聊天机器人包
what if packages is like a bunch of
怎么样的包就像一堆
different programming functionality just
不同的编程功能
bundled into a package and you can take
捆绑成一个包，你可以采取
different functions out of that package
该包装中的不同功能
as you wish so right now all that we're
正如你所愿，现在我们所有的一切
doing is getting the chat bot
做的是获取聊天机器人
functionality from this chatter bot from
来自这个聊天机器人的功能
this chatter bot package so we're gonna
这个聊天机器人套餐所以我们要去
initialize a new chat bot now we'll give
现在我们将给出一个新的聊天机器人
it a variable we'll just name it chat
它是一个变量，我们只是将它命名为聊天
bot and so now our chat bot anytime we
机器人，所以现在我们的聊天机器人随时随地
want to reference our chat bot we can do
想要参考我们可以做的聊天机器人
it by
它
accessing this variable chat bot that we
访问我们的这个变量聊天机器人
just created so we're gonna use this see
刚刚创建，所以我们将使用这个看
how this is getting highlighted here
这是如何突出显示的
we're going to use this chat bot
我们将使用这个聊天机器人
functionality to create a new chat bot
创建新聊天机器人的功能
and save it into this variable here so
并保存到这个变量这里这么
we want to make a Charlie chat bot and
我们想做一个查理聊天机器人
we need to give it a trainer because it
我们需要给它一个培训师，因为它
needs to know how it's going to respond
需要知道它将如何回应
to being given language okay it needs to
给予语言好的它需要
know it needs to know the way that we're
知道它需要知道我们的方式
going to speak to it and interact with
去说话吧和互动
it so we're gonna give it a trainer for
所以我们要给它一个培训师
that and the trainer we're gonna use is
那个和我们要用的训练师是
in chatter bot trainers dot list trainer
在聊天机器人培训师点列表培训师
that should be it to make a brand new
这应该是一个全新的
chat bot step two so now we need to
聊天机器人第二步所以现在我们 需要
train the chat bot we just created on
培养我们刚创建聊天机器人
examples of things that we might say to
我们可能会说的事情的例子
it and the way that we want it to
它和我们想要它的方式
respond so we do that by getting this
回应所以我们通过这样做来做到这一点
chat bot variable from earlier and just
来自早期和刚才的聊天机器人变量
saying chat bot train now we're gonna
说聊天机器人火车现在我们要去
give it examples of what we'd like it to
举例说明我们喜欢的内容
say and examples of what people might
说和人们可能的例子
say to the chat bot so let's say we want
对聊天机器人 说，让我们说我们想要
to make a chat bot that can book flights
制作一个可以预订航班的聊天机器人
for us so first the chat bot might say
对我们来说，首先聊天机器人可能会说
hi can i hi can I help you let's say hi
嗨，我可以嗨，我可以帮助你打个招呼
how can I help you , and we might say
我怎么能帮助你，我们可以说
back to that I'd like to book a flight
回到那我想预订航班
to Iceland comma and the bot would
冰岛逗号和机器人会
respond okay I'll say I have let's say
回答没关系我会说我已经说过了
your flight has been booked
您的航班已被预订
bang alright that should be good and now
好吧，现在应该是好的
whoops test
哎呀测试
chatbot so now our final step let's test
聊天机器人所以现在我们的最后一步让我们测试一下
it out let's see how this works
它让我们看看它是如何工作的
chatbot oh let's come up with a query so
chatbot哦让我们想出一个查询
let's say we want to book a flight
假设我们想预订航班
that's what we want to do we want to go
这就是我们想要做我们想要去
to I'd like to book a flight where do
以我想预订航班在哪里
you want to go where do you want to go
你想去哪里你想去
where do you want to go no man you guys
你想在哪里找不到你的男人
don't respond to me I'd like to book a
不要回应我，我想预订一个
flight to Gibraltar get response and we
飞往直布罗陀的航班得到回复，我们
pass it the query so we've got a place
传递它的查询，所以我们有一个地方
we want to go now we need to do chatbot
我们想去的地方，现在我们需要做的聊天机器人
dot get response because we want it to
斑点得到回应，因为我们希望它
respond to the thing that we're telling
回应我们所说的事情
it right now
它现在
so we give it our query in these
所以我们在这些中给出我们的查询
parentheses right here and let's just
圆括号就在这里，让我们一起来吧
put this in a variable call it response
把它放在变量中调用它的响应
and then to finish off will print the
然后完成将打印出来
response to see what our chat bot says
回应看看我们的聊天机器人说的话
oh I forgot we used lists trainer which
哦，我忘了我们用过列表训练器
needs the it needs the language examples
需要它需要语言示例
in a list so I'm just going to wrap
在一个列表中， 所以我要打包
these in a list right here so now I've
这些在这里列表，所以现在我
got a list of samples and this should
有一个样本列表，这应该
work now cool
现在工作很酷
we go into Gibraltar cool so there you
我们进入直布罗陀很酷，也让你有
go there's a chatbot obviously very
去那里聊天机器人显然非常
basic and it doesn't actually book us a
基本的，它实际上没有预订我们
flight but I think that's pretty cool
飞行但我觉得这很酷
how I mean look at how little training
我怎么说看看训练有多少
we had to do to get it to respond
我们必须做到让它回应
meaningfully so there's an idea of some
有意义的是有一些想法
chatbot code that could be written out
可以写出的聊天机器人代码
in the wild somewhere and yeah there you
在某处野外，是的，你呢
go I hope you enjoy it I hope you
去， 我希望你喜欢它，我希望你
learned something about chatbots
了解了聊天机器人的一些知识
and I hope you keep learning about
我希望你继续学习
machine learning because it's a super
机器学习， 因为它是超级的
interesting field I'm Lewis with Palo
有趣的领域我是刘易斯与帕洛
Alto education signing out for now
奥拓教育现在退出